ALICIA N. GORTON

Sacramento, CA 95834

Phone: 217-377-7697 | Email: aliciagorton17@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedIn: linkedin.com/in/alicia-gorton | GitHub: github.com/alicia-gorton | Portfolio: alicia-gorton | Po

SUMMARY

A recent graduate of a Full Stack Web Developer bootcamp taught by UC Davis, with a MERN focus. Passionate to merge professional background in healthcare with technology. Adept communicator, organizer, and problem solver. Confident in ability to utilize learned skills and ability to strengthen any team.

Expert in customer service and client satisfaction. Trained at prioritizing tasks, being efficient with time and dealing in high stress environments. Previously a nurse and behavioral technician specializing in children who have Autism. Those experiences have enabled a strong sense of self and what others may need but can't always articulate. Aim to build better software experiences, driven to make a difference, motivated to work as part of a team to diagnose and solve complex problems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React MongoDB MySQL Node Express JavaScript Bootstrap

PROJECTS

Kuma | bit.ly/3mmBBDA | bit.ly/3mkn6A1

- Kuma is an application that allows people to create profiles for their pets and compare traits with other members' pets to find playdates for them while also meeting new people with similar interests.
- Learned how user credentials, web sessions and relational databases work. Contributed front end in user interface design, page layouts and page designs.
- Built using Sequelize, Passport, Express, Node.js, Handlebars, MySQL, Bootstrap, and JavaScript.

Chuck Norris Fan Page | Code: bit.ly/3jtaVik | Live: bit.ly/34rx9wV

- Chuck Norris "Fan Page" with retro throwback twist, reminiscent of early web experiences and design.
- Learned the DOM, making fetch requests with APIs and creating event listeners to respond to user interactivity. Contribution focused on javascript, creating responsive events and utilizing API's.
- Built using two server-side APIs, a third-party API, Javascript, and Bulma.

Workout Tracker | Code: http://bit.ly/2HILfRV | Live: bit.ly/2HEML7Y

- An app where users are able to create, track, and view daily workouts.
- Built using MongoDB, express and Node.js.

PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCE

Registered Behavioral Technician (RBT)

October 2019 - September 2020

Maxium Health Services

Sacramento, CA

Worked in multiple environments to provide ABA therapy; including homes and in schools. Responsible for implementation of the plan of care and a strong relationship with families involved. Diligent documentation, self-sufficient in problem solving, and responsive to all parties involved.

Key Accomplishments: Encouraged and with recommendations by direct supervisor to apply for promotions within the company, along with being told by families how pivotal my care was to their child.

Registered Behavioral Technician (RBT)

Intercare Therapy Inc.

June 2019 - October 2020 Sacramento. CA

Delivered direct ABA therapy to children with autism as well as a strong relationship with families involved. On a team that spearheaded the first rollout of online documentation in the company, a part of discussions of how to improve usability and ease within the app.

Key Accomplishments: Passed exam for the state of California to become a Registered Behavioral Technician.

Behavioral Technician

May 2018 - May 2019

Comprehensive Early Autism Services

Chicago, IL

Provided ABA therapy to children with autism, in multiple settings such as community, school, and home environments. Responsibilities included detailed documentation, coaching for teachers, and ability to transmit important information to all parties. Learned invaluable de-escalation and crisis prevention techniques.

Key Accomplishments: Passed CPI (crisis prevention courses).

Undergraduate Research Assistant

June 2016 - May 2017

Comprehensive Early Autism Services

Urbana, IL

Helped to design materials for experiments. Tested toddlers, preschoolers, and adults in experiments. Responsible for transcribing transcription, utilizing excel, coding of children's speech, and coding visual fixations into from video recordings.

Key Accomplishments: Repeatedly highered back for three semesters.

Licensed Practical Nurse

July 2013 - June 2014

Carle Foundation Hospital

Urbana, IL

Delivered nursing to patients in outpatient procedures, while also being cross-trained in the scheduling department. Responsible for executing evaluations, interventions and modification of the plan of care individualized to each patient. Impeccable at communication, organizing of materials, and management of time in the production room or scheduling offices.

Key Accomplishments: Across trained throughout the department.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of California at Davis, CA

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor of Science in Psychology: University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign, IL

A breadth and depth in the study of human and animal behavior. Emphasis on statistical analysis, research techniques and methodologies. An understanding in the biological process of behavior.

Licensed Practical Nurse: Parkland College, Champaign, IL

An accredited program, focused on teaching transferable skills through long-term care facilities, clinics, and hospitals. Graduates are eligible to take the licensing examination.